<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on tunzor</title>
    <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on tunzor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 18:56:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tunzor.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a dockerized two-tier app on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/k8s-two-tier-deploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 18:56:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/k8s-two-tier-deploy/</guid>
      <description>For a great deal of developers, myself included, doing something is the preferred method of learning as opposed to reading how to do it. When I was wrapping my head around using kubernetes to manage my docker containers, I found that creating a deployment from scratch was invaluable. I&amp;rsquo;d like to walk you through that deployment and explain everything along the way.
Before we jump in, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip: Make a directory and enter it with one command</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/mkdir-and-enter-one-liner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 18:41:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/mkdir-and-enter-one-liner/</guid>
      <description>We all make directories. It&amp;rsquo;s one way that we attempt to bring order to the chaos that is the filesystem.
We&amp;rsquo;re also pretty lazy. Creating a new directory and navigating into it is usually a two command affair:
mkdir order-i-say cd order-i-say  Not anymore it isn&amp;rsquo;t:
mkdir quickly-now &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd $_   Explanation
$_ is the last argument passed to the previous command. In our case, it&amp;rsquo;s the directory name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running a Hugo generated site on Github Pages and Google Cloud Storage</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/hugo-on-gh-and-gcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 09:45:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/hugo-on-gh-and-gcs/</guid>
      <description>Hugo, I just recently discovered, is one of many static site generators. You feed them content in the form of Markdown files and they spit out HTML pages which you can then provide to a web server for hosting.
This in and of itself might not be very interesting but the potential hosting environments are what particularly interest me.
Why go static? Since the pages are HTML, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about having a server dynamically render a page when a user makes a request to your site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>