<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>godot on tunzor</title>
    <link>https://tunzor.github.io/tags/godot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in godot on tunzor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tunzor.github.io/tags/godot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Game in One Day</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/making-a-game-in-one-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/making-a-game-in-one-day/</guid>
      <description>Making a game is tough. We&amp;rsquo;ve read it in countless books and articles, heard it on podcasts, and seen it in the first hand video accounts of developers.
Making a game in a limited amount of time is tougher. Looming deadlines are always in the back of your head and crunch time seems to be an industry standard practice that doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be going away.
Making a game in the limited time span of one or two days should be the toughest then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): I don&#39;t have ALL day</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-11/</guid>
      <description> Click here to play the most up-to-date version
Easy Peasy What&amp;rsquo;s changed since last time? v0.13.0  Impatient customers! Customers will no longer wait indefinitely for their order  A countdown timer starts when the customer arrives and will change their shirt colour the closer it gets to 0  Shirt colour now starts out green and progresses to yellow and finally red  Serving a customer will now grant points based on how long they&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting The time extension granted on correctly served orders is now related to how close the customer is to leaving  More time is granted the closer they are to leaving   Difficulty levels  Starts out with just one customer and increases the number of customers for each level gained One additional customer will spawn with each new level starting at level 3 Level is increased after serving 3 customers correctly Level and customers served in it are displayed above the score as: CURRENT_LEVEL - CUSTOMERS_SERVED  Bug fixes  Customers no longer change state and leave after game over Customers no longer change state on start screen   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): Sugar Rush</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-10/</guid>
      <description> Click here to play the most up-to-date version
RTFM What&amp;rsquo;s changed since last time? v0.12.0  Added instructions page  Includes background &amp;ldquo;story&amp;rdquo;, how to play, and controls  Sugar! Do do doo do do doo&amp;hellip;  New orders: donut and pop (soda) with two item parts each Updated order matching code to work with varying sizes of orders instead of just 3 items All current orders and their parts are pictured below:   Updated food spawning code to only spawn items that aren&amp;rsquo;t currently being held  If all current order items are held, then ANY food item in the game can spawn (even if it&amp;rsquo;s not in a current customer&amp;rsquo;s order)  Added a new font  Unified all text to use the same font  Bug fixes  Game crashing bug occurred if game over was caused by all customers leaving   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): I&#39;ll Tell You What I Want</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-9/</guid>
      <description> Click here to play the most up-to-date version
Variety is the Spice of Life What&amp;rsquo;s changed since last time? v0.11.0  Customers now show their order above their heads!  Moving in front to interact will tint the order based on what Chef is currently holding: red if incorrect, green if correct (provides a quick way of seeing if held order is correct)  Two new orders!  New orders: pizza and ice cream sundae Food items (parts of orders) will only spawn if they&amp;rsquo;re in at least one customer&amp;rsquo;s order All current orders and their parts are pictured below:   Added final score to game over screen Removed garbage can interaction popup Bug fixes  Reduced number of items needed to trigger a game over (was too high after adding &amp;ldquo;Slide to Move&amp;rdquo; area)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): I Like to Move It, Move It</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 01:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-8/</guid>
      <description> Click here to play the most up-to-date version
Just One for Me, Please What&amp;rsquo;s changed since last time? v0.10.0  Retooled input and movement  Added a &amp;ldquo;Slide to Move&amp;rdquo; area: tap and slide in it to move Chef Tap on brown area (with customers and stools) to interact Mouse input  Emulates touch input now (must move mouse in the &amp;ldquo;Slide to Move&amp;rdquo; area and hold down left button to move) Click on the brown area to interact OR right click anywhere   Added timer to customer to stop spamming of incorrect orders (protects against multiple accidental interaction inputs) Made the area above the garbage can a &amp;ldquo;safe area&amp;rdquo;: food won&amp;rsquo;t spawn over it Removed desktop input toggle options (keyboard and mouse inputs are still usable) Updated start screen instructions Bug fixes  Fixed bug that served multiple times when interact input pressed once Fixed bug that didn&amp;rsquo;t allow scrolling of instructions on touch screens Fixed bug that crashed game when pressing a key while holding mouse button   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): Time to Start Me Up</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 01:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-7/</guid>
      <description> Click here to play the most up-to-date version
Disco Fever What&amp;rsquo;s changed since last time?  Fancy new start screen!  Colourful title now shows you what you&amp;rsquo;re playing Instructions on how to play in a scrollable text area  Added a round timer of 60 seconds  Serving correct orders increases time available by 3 seconds Serving incorrect orders decreases time available by 2 seconds   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): IPO Time</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 01:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-6/</guid>
      <description> Click here to play the most up-to-date version
Mobile-ize What&amp;rsquo;s changed since last time?  Diner Drop can now be played in your browser!  Works on both desktop and mobile All future builds will be published at that link so check back for updates  Multiple input methods available  On desktop you can choose to play with mouse or keyboard controls  Mouse: Move Chef by moving the mouse and click anywhere in the bottom area (where the stools are) to interact with whatever is highlighted in front of Chef Keyboard: Move Chef left with a or left arrow, right with d or right arrow, and interact with things with s or down arrow You can toggle them on and off with either m for mouse controls or k for keyboard controls (shown by either an M or K in the top left of the screen)  On mobile, Chef will follow your finger much like the mouse movement above  Tap and drag to move Chef and tap anywhere in the bottom area (where the stools are) to interact with whatever is highlighted in front of Chef   Game over screen now shows a message about why the player lost  Game over now shows if you have too many held food items  Bug fixes  Fixed food items spawning off screen Only the top item of the food stack being held has collision detection (gif above demonstrates how the sides have no collision) Fixed issue where tapping and dragging to move on mobile would cause Chef to serve to a customer unintentionally   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): It&#39;s a big one! Game Over, Man!</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 01:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-5/</guid>
      <description>Click here to play the most up-to-date version
I Want to Speak to the Manager! What&amp;rsquo;s changed since last time? A LOT!  Customers aren&amp;rsquo;t taking your crap anymore; game over!  Serving the same customer 3 incorrect orders (partial or complete) will push them over the edge and cause them to leave If all (currently 3) customers leave, it&amp;rsquo;s game over Serving the correct order to a customer will despawn them, increase the score, and spawn a new one at a random available spot  Added game over screen with restart button  Endlessly drops food until restart pressed (super fun to watch) Stops collision detection on Chef and locks movement input  Generalized code around customer&amp;rsquo;s order (no longer hard coding burger as the only order) New font added for customers&amp;rsquo; feedback  Text will appear towards the centre of the screen depending on where the customer is (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): Front and Centre</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 01:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-4/</guid>
      <description> Click here to play the most up-to-date version
Table for Three What&amp;rsquo;s changed since last time?  More customers!  3 customers will now spawn (in random positions!) at the counter waiting for their order  UI update: interactive objects (customers and garbage can) now start out dimmed and become fully bright when Chef is in front of them and can interact  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): What&#39;ll ya have?</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-3/</guid>
      <description> Click here to play the most up-to-date version
The Points Don&amp;rsquo;t Matter What&amp;rsquo;s changed since last time?  A customer has finally arrived!  The player can now stand in front of them and press down to serve them the order that Chef is currently holding Customers will provide feedback text on whether the order is correct or not Serving an order (correct or not) will remove it from Chef  Player now has a score to increase (or decrease&amp;hellip;)  Serving a correct order yields a point and an incorrect order deducts a point   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): Variety is the Spice of Life</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 01:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-2/</guid>
      <description> Click here to play the most up-to-date version
Catch Me If You Can What&amp;rsquo;s changed since last time?  Chef can now catch and hold the falling food; allowing orders to be made All three parts of the burger now spawn  Bottom: the bun and lettuce Middle: the patty and tomato Top: the onion and bun  The garbage can interaction now lets Chef throw away their currently held order  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot in a gif(fy): A game dev blog told through gifs</title>
      <link>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunzor.github.io/posts/godot-diner-drop-1/</guid>
      <description>Click here to play the most up-to-date version
As outlined in a previous post, I started developing a game with the Godot engine about catching falling food and serving it to demanding customers, aptly named Diner Drop.
In this series of posts I intend on showcasing the progress made on the game&amp;rsquo;s development through the greatest of all Internet formats: the gif. A lot can be said with pictures (especially moving ones) but I may also include a few words too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>